Josh Griffiths

3 Vincent Hall, La Rue du Becquet Vincent Jersey JE35FH Tel: +44 7471 836559 joshgriffiths.co.uk E: josh@hakuna.co.uk

Profile

First Class BSc Mathematics Graduate from University of Southampton with primary interests in machine learning and data analytics. Has experience in computational statistics and machine learning implementation in R and Python, both from scratch and using standard libraries including PyTorch, SciPy, Numpy and Pandas. Currently reading MSc Data Analytics at Queen Mary University London for expected graduation with distinction September 2022.

Skills & Interests

- Machine Learning I achieved a distinction grade in my final undergraduate project on the implementation and comparison of classification methods, with emphasis on Random Forests. I also have a wide variety of machine learning projects on various topics on both supervised and unsupervised learning on my website.
- <u>Python</u> Using Numpy, SciPy and Pandas, I have implemented Convolutional Neural Networks, K-Nearest
 Neighbour Models and Multinomial Logistic Regression Models from scratch for use in image classification,
 with reliable high testing accuracy. I have also worked with unsupervised/semi-supervised learning methods
 for use in clustering and dimensionality reduction. I have also worked in a group setting in Python, utilising
 Git.
- R I have worked in RStudio and RMarkup for my university studies, mostly in data visualisation using GGPlot and Matplotlib.
- Front End Dev In my free time I enjoy adding to my repertoire of skills, most recently by creating my portfolio website using plain html and Bootstrap.
- Chess Avid chess fan and player, with an online rating in the 95th percentile worldwide.

Work Experience

Intertrust
Student Administrator
(Summer Placement)
August 2019 – September 2019

Developed experience using Excel and other industry-standard administration software. Assisted with handling data for and communicating with regular high-value customers.

Private Maths Tutoring 2016 – August 2019 Assessing abilities of pupils in a 1-on-1 setting and using this to create effective teaching plans. Achieved notable improvements in exam performance.

Education

Queen Mary University London Sep 2021 - Sep 2022 MSc Data Analytics (ongoing)

University of Southampton Sep 2018 – June 2021 BSc Mathematics: First Class Hons.

Victoria College Sep 2010 – June 2015 A Level: A* - OCR GCE Mathematics (May 2017)
A - OCR MEI Further Mathematics (May 2018)

A - AQA Psychology (May 2018) B - OCR AS Science (May 2015)

GCSE: A** Further Maths (May 2015)

7 A* (including Maths, French, Science) (May 2014/15) 4 A (including English Lang, English Lit) (May 2015)